What are you?
Kau ini apa?
I told you.
Sudah kubilang.
I'm a god.
Aku dewa.
Lord Habaek.
Tuan Habaek.
Your abilities...
Kemampuanmu…
Your power...
Kekuatanmu…
It's finally back!
Akhirnya kembali!
How could this happen?
Bagaimana ini bisa terjadi?
How did you...
Bagaimana kau…
How did you regain your power?
Bagaimana kekuatanmu bisa kembali?
Please try it again.
Ulangi lagi.
Goodness.
Astaga.
Please try it.
Cobalah.
How can it be gone again?
Kenapa bisa hilang lagi?
It's all your fault.
Ini semua salahmu.
It's your fault.
Ini salahmu.
It's all your fault!
Ini semua salahmu!
Because of you,
Gara-gara kau,
do you know how I've lived?
kau tahu seperti apa aku hidup?
It's so unfair.
Sangat tidak adil.
No!
Tidak.
Die.
Mati.
Die!
Mati!
Please save me!
Tolong selamatkan aku.
I told you.
Sudah kubilang.
I'm a god.
Aku dewa.
I'm still dreaming.
Aku masih bermimpi.
This dream is long.
Mimpinya panjang.
I'm still in a dream.
Aku masih dalam mimpi.
No, you're not.
Kau tidak bermimpi.
-I am. -No, you aren't.
- Mimpi. - Tidak.
How can his power...
Bagaimana kekuatannya...
I can't believe this.
Aku tak percaya ini.
It's impossible.
Ini mustahil.
What do we do?
Kita harus bagaimana?
Impossible.
Mustahil.
I must be dreaming.
Aku pasti bermimpi.
It's impossible.
Ini mustahil.
Right. It must be my feelings of guilt.
Benar. Ini pasti rasa bersalahku.
My condition must be worse than I thought.
Kondisiku pasti lebih buruk dari dugaanku.
In addition to hearing things, I'm seeing things too.
Selain mendengar suara-suara, aku juga berhalusinasi.
It's okay.
Tak apa-apa.
I'll take some medicine. It's just my feelings of guilt.
Aku akan minum obat. Ini hanya rasa bersalahku.
It's all your fault.
Ini semua salahmu.
It's all your fault!
Ini semua salahmu!
Because of you...
Gara-gara kau...
Oh, my gosh. Let go of me!
Astaga, lepaskan aku!
-Don't! -Relax.
- Jangan! - Tenang.
You run away every time.
Kau selalu melarikan diri.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Who was he?
Siapa dia?
-I don't know. -Think carefully.
- Entahlah. - Pikirkan baik-baik.
Does anyone hold a grudge against you?
Ada yang dendam padamu?
This is a problem. You can't even report it.
Ini masalah. Kau bahkan tak bisa melaporkannya.
I should...
Sebaiknya aku...
report it.
melaporkannya.
Someone was trying to kill you,
Ada yang coba membunuhmu,
and the king of the Land of Water saved you.
dan Raja Negeri Air menyelamatkanmu.
You can't say that to anyone.
Jangan bilang pada siapa pun.
Who would believe that?
Siapa yang akan percaya?
How could he throw you from that high up?
Bagaimana dia bisa mendorongmu dari ketinggian itu?
He's so evil.
Dia jahat sekali.
Is this the house you were making such a fuss about?
Apa ini rumah yang sangat kau cemaskan itu?
I didn't make a fuss.
Aku tak cemas.
Go in.
Masuklah.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Are you...
Apa kau...
really a god,
benar-benar dewa,
not a monster or a ghost?
bukan monster atau hantu?
-Are you really a deity? -My goodness.
- Kau dewa sungguhan? - Astaga.
You're so different from the God I know.
Kau sangat berbeda dari dewa yang biasa kutahu.
Let's go.
Ayo.
What are you doing?
Sedang apa kau?
The holy foot of Lord Habaek has crossed your threshold.
Kaki suci Dewa Habaek telah melewati ambangmu.
-Sorry? -The god is inside your gate now.
- Apa? - Sang dewa ada di dalam gerbangmu.
You have to let him in.
Kau harus persilakan dia masuk.
I have to...
Aku harus…
Hey. Wait.
Hei, tunggu.
Wait.
Tunggu.
Do you believe Lord Habaek is the God of Water?
Apa kau percaya Tuan Habaek adalah Dewa Air?
Answer me. Do you believe it?
Jawab. Apa kau percaya?
Do you believe it?
Kau percaya?
I do.
Aku percaya.
Yet you want him to leave your house?
Namun, kau ingin dia pergi dari rumahmu?
I don't want to go in either.
Aku juga tak mau masuk.
Let's say the god gives up on this house out of anger.
Katakanlah dewa menyerah soal rumah ini karena marah.
I've given up a long time ago.
Aku sudah lama menyerah.
That means your family will start to attract
Itu berarti keluargamu akan mulai menarik
all the kinds of bad luck in the world
semua jenis kesialan di dunia
and all good luck will stay out of your house.
dan keberuntungan akan menjauh dari rumahmu.
All your descendants will die before they turn 20.
Semua keturunanmu akan mati sebelum usia 20.
In other words, you'll be punished for not having faith.
Dengan kata lain, kau akan dihukum karena tak percaya.
Sorry?
Apa?
If you were not sure,
Jika kau tak yakin,
you should not have let the god go through your gate.
jangan biarkan dewa melewati gerbangmu.
I didn't let him in.
Aku tak membiarkannya masuk.
I mean...
Maksudku...
I live here.
aku tinggal di sini.
I can't believe this.
Aku tak percaya.
You ungrateful woman.
Dasar wanita tak tahu terima kasih.
How dare you make me stay here?
Kau ingin aku tinggal di sini?
Where is she?
Di mana dia?
It was hard to get in here.
Sulit masuk ke sini.
If I had known how this place looked, I wouldn't have come in.
Jika aku tahu tempatnya begini, aku takkan masuk.
You don't understand.
Kau tak mengerti.
Having a roof over your head... makes a huge difference.
Punya tempat untuk berteduh
Please don't worry too much.
Jangan terlalu cemas.
The owner of the duck boat tour company is fond of me.
Pemilik perusahaan tur kapal bebek menyukaiku.
I'll do everything in my power to make sure you will be comfortable.
Aku akan berusaha semampuku agar kau nyaman.
The world of mankind is actually a pretty fun place.
Dunia umat manusia sebenarnya tempat yang menyenangkan.
You should have some fun.
Kau harus bersenang-senang.
That sleazy old man.
Pria tua busuk itu.
That blabbermouth brought me bad luck.
Pembual itu bawa kesialan untukku.
No way. This is crazy.
Tak mungkin. Ini gila.
This can't be.
Tak mungkin.
HABAEK
HABAEK
SONG IL-GOOK
SONG IL-GOOK
HAE MO-SU, LADY YUHWA
HAE MO-SU, NYONYA YUHWA
JUN KWANG-RYUL, JUMONG, GOGURYEO, OH YEON-SOO
JUN KWANG-RYUL, JUMONG, GOGURYEO, OH YEON-SOO
GOD OF WATER
DEWA AIR
That's impossible.
Tidak mungkin.
This can't be.
Ini tidak mungkin.
I'm in Gyeryongsan to practice meditation.
Aku di Gyeryongsan, latihan meditasi.
Don't contact me.
Jangan hubungi aku.
Have a good day.
Semoga harimu menyenangkan.
-Bye. -Have a good day.
- Dah. - Semoga harimu menyenangkan.
That's right!
Benar!
Don't they have the power to make anything happen?
Bukankah mereka bisa mewujudkan sesuatu?
Can you make that become mine?
Bisakah kau membuatnya menjadi milikku?
If you faithfully carry out your duties as my servant,
Jika kau setia jadi pelayanku,
I can certainly make that thing for you.
aku bisa mewujudkannya untukmu.
That too?
Itu juga?
Yes. All I need to do is snap my fingers.
Ya. Aku cukup menjentikkan jari.
That's the point.
Itu maksudku.
Why does he keep leeching off of me?
Kenapa dia terus memperalatku?
Look.
Dengar.
I want to become richer than Sheikh Mansour.
Aku ingin lebih kaya dari Syekh Mansour.
-Make me some gold now. -Right now, I can't.
- Buatkan aku emas sekarang. - Aku tak bisa.
I told you that I'm in a bit of a situation.
Aku sedang dalam kesulitan.
A situation?
Kesulitan?
What can it be?
Kesulitan apa?
He's in a bit of a bind.
Dia sedang kesulitan.
You must think it's weird he's like that when he's a god.
Kau pasti berpikir tindakannya aneh padahal dia dewa.
-Yes. -There's a reason.
- Ya. - Ada alasannya.
It's because...
Itu karena...
You don't need to tell me. I hate listening to others' hard-luck stories.
Jangan ceritakan. Aku benci mendengar cerita malang orang lain.
Oh, okay.
Baiklah.
Do you have any leftover rice?
Apa kau punya nasi sisa?
He's here to find the sacred stones?
Dia kemari mencari batu keramat?
Yes. He just has to get them from the three gods here,
Ya. Dia harus mengambilnya dari tiga dewa di sini,
and we were told it wouldn't be hard.
dan diberi tahu itu takkan sulit.
But...
Tapi…
I have no idea why it got so messed up.
Entah kenapa jadi kacau.
He's never been through an ordeal like this in the last 2,800 years.
Dia tak pernah melalui cobaan begini dalam 2.800 tahun terakhir.
He must be extremely distressed now.
Dia pasti sangat tertekan sekarang.
He hasn't even been able to take warm baths, which he loves.
Berendam air hangat pun ia tak bisa.
What?
Apa?
He's 2,800 years old?
Dia berusia 2.800 tahun?
Are you sure you don't want to know more?
Yakin tak mau tahu lebih jauh?
Yes. I really hate having to listen to others' hard-luck stories.
Ya. Aku benci harus mendengar cerita malang orang lain.
-Then why do you have that job? -Sorry?
- Lalu kenapa pekerjaanmu begitu? - Apa?
As a doctor, you have to listen to people's stories all the time.
Sebagai dokter, kau selalu mendengarkan cerita orang.
He lost his power?
Kekuatannya hilang?
Goodness. Then he's nothing.
Astaga. Maka dia bukan siapa-siapa.
My gosh, what's he doing?
Ya ampun. Sedang apa dia?
What on earth are you doing now?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Gosh, you can't be doing that here.
Astaga, jangan lakukan itu di sini.
-Come out right now! -Be quiet.
- Keluar sekarang! - Diam.
I said come out right now!
Keluar sekarang!
No. Don't. Don't get up. Just stay there.
Jangan. Jangan berdiri. Tetap di sana.
What do you want?
Apa maumu?
Please. Just stay in there.
Kumohon, tetap di sana.
Here.
Ini.
-I wanted to take a warm bath. -Warm bath?
- Aku mau mandi air hangat. - Mandi air hangat?
He hasn't even been able to take warm baths, which he loves.
Dia bahkan tak bisa mandi air hangat.
I don't need it.
Aku tak butuh itu.
Yes, you do.
Ya, kau butuh.
People will see it and report you to the police.
Orang-orang akan melihatmu dan melaporkanmu ke polisi.
The police will come to get you. You know what "police" is, right?
Lalu kau ditangkap polisi. Kau tahu "polisi", 'kan?
People will report me to the police for taking a bath? How mean.
Orang melaporkanku ke polisi karena aku mandi? Jahat sekali.
That's not why people would call the police.
Bukan itu alasan orang lapor polisi.
No? Then what's the reason?
Bukan? Lalu apa alasannya?
Indecent exposure. It's an offense against public--
Tindakan tak senonoh. Itu pelanggaran publik...
Can you pull up the towel?
Bisa kau tarik ke atas handuknya?
Pull it up, please.
Tolong tarik ke atas.
Are you going to keep ordering me around?
Kau akan terus memerintahku?
Have you forgotten that I'm a god and that I'm your master?
Apa kau lupa bahwa aku dewa dan aku adalah tuanmu?
I don't know about that, but I heard you lost your power.
Aku tak yakin soal itu, tapi kudengar kekuatanmu hilang.
Can a god still be called a god without his power?
Bisakah dewa tetap disebut dewa tanpa kekuatannya?
I'm getting a bad feeling.
Perasaanku tak enak.
That's right.
Benar.
My power has been on and off, but I'll regain it soon.
Kekuatanku timbul tenggelam, tapi nanti akan kuperoleh lagi.
And...
Dan…
I guess you haven't heard this.
sepertinya kau belum dengar ini.
Does losing my power mean I'm not a god?
Apakah karena kehilangan kekuatan, berarti aku bukan dewa?
Will you no longer be human if you lose your human nature?
Apa kau bukan manusia jika kehilangan sifat manusiamu?
Do you still not know
Kau masih tak tahu
why those flowers kept talking to you and drove you crazy?
kenapa bunga-bunga itu terus bicara dan membuatmu gila?
I'll help you remember it.
Kubantu kau mengingatnya.
Don't you dare...
Jangan coba-coba...
test me.
mengujiku.
You stopped hearing them talking because you helped me.
Kau berhenti mendengar mereka karena kau membantuku.
If you betray me, it'll start happening again.
Jika berkhianat, akan muncul lagi.
-Is that a threat? -"A threat"?
- Apa ini ancaman? - Ancaman?
Blame your foolish ancestors who made such a promise with the gods.
Bencilah pada nenek moyangmu yang membuat janji dengan para dewa.
I don't want to stay here for a long time.
Aku tak mau di sini terlalu lama.
I don't even expect you to help me resolve my situation.
Aku bahkan tak berharap kau membantuku mengatasi kesulitanku.
Just make sure that my stay here isn't uncomfortable by serving me well.
Pastikan saja keadaannya nyaman selagi aku di sini dengan melayaniku.
If you still can't accept it,
Jika masih tak bisa kau terima,
repay me for everything I've done. I helped you
balaslah semua jasaku.
Fine. Repaying you makes more sense than living as your servant.
Baik. Membalas jasamu lebih masuk akal daripada hidup jadi pelayanmu.
But don't forget that this is the human world.
Tapi jangan lupa bahwa ini adalah dunia manusia.
It's 2017, and you're in Seoul, Korea.
Ini tahun 2017 dan kau di Seoul, Korea.
If you want to live here, don't take baths wherever you want.
Jika ingin tinggal di sini, jangan mandi di mana saja sesukamu.
And humans aren't objects.
Manusia bukan objek.
You can't own people.
Kau tak bisa memiliki orang lain.
Servant? Master?
Pelayan? Tuan?
Not a chance.
Enak saja.
One more thing!
Satu hal lagi!
If you kiss me again...
Jika kau menciumku lagi,
-That is my right. -...I'll report you to the police.
- Itu hakku. - Kulaporkan kau ke polisi.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH DOCTOR YUN SO-A
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED DOKTER YUN SO-A
-Are you okay? -Who are you?
- Kau baik-baik saja? - Siapa kau?
I'm his guardian.
Aku pelindungnya.
Who are you, really?
Siapa kau sebenarnya?
Hye-ra.
Hye-ra.
It's been a while, Mr. Shin.
Lama tak jumpa, Tn. Shin.
I'm sorry about yesterday. It was our mistake.
Maaf soal kemarin. Itu kesalahan kami.
You don't need to apologize for my crazy fan causing a scene.
Kau tak perlu minta maaf karena penggemarku berulah.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH DOCTOR YUN SO-A
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED DOKTER YUN SO-A
I think she was just trying her best to treat her patient.
Kupikir dia hanya berusaha sebaik-baiknya untuk merawat pasiennya.
Do you know her?
Kau mengenalnya?
She's a good doctor.
Dia dokter yang cakap.
I'm not so sure about that. I just know that she is rude.
Aku tak yakin soal itu. Yang kuahu dia kasar.
Have you ever worked with an actor who is always sorry?
Pernah bekerja dengan aktor yang selalu menyesal?
-Is there an actor like that? -Ji Sung.
- Apa ada aktor seperti itu? - Ji Sung.
Excuse me.
Aku undur diri.
Was it not funny?
Apa itu tidak lucu?
Here is the list of the owners of the site for Block World.
Ini daftar pemilik lahan untuk Block World.
By the way, Chairman Shin seems to want to get involved with the bidding too.
Omong-omong, Direktur Shin
Don't worry, and focus on dealing with the landowners.
Jangan khawatir dan fokuslah dengan pemilik tanah.
Yes, sir. I'll get in touch with them today.
Baik, Pak. Saya hubungi mereka hari ini.
Would you like a meeting with Chairman Shin?
Anda bersedia rapat dengan Direktur Shin?
Yes.
Ya.
By the way, do you know what handsome scissors are called?
Omong-omong, kau tahu sebutan gunting tampan?
-Sorry? -Handsome guy.
- Maaf? - Pria tampan.
Mr. Shin.
Tn. Shin.
In my favorite comedy show's new segment, they make these kind of jokes.
Di segmen acara komedi kesukaanku, mereka membuat lelucon seperti ini.
It's so funny.
Sangat lucu.
You don't watch much television. Why do you like comedy shows?
Kau tak banyak menonton televisi. Kenapa suka acara komedi?
Do you want to know a secret?
Apa kau mau tahu satu rahasia?
To be honest, I don't find it funny. I don't understand why people laugh.
Sejujurnya, menurutku tak lucu. Aku tak paham kenapa orang tertawa.
What I'm most jealous about is humans' sense of humor.
Yang paling membuatku iri adalah selera humor manusia.
No matter how hard I try, I just don't get it.
Kucoba semampuku, aku tetap tak paham.
LIST OF LANDOWNERS, YUN SO-A
DAFTAR PEMILIK LAHAN, YUN SO-A
I keep running into this girl,
Aku kerap menemukan gadis ini,
Yun So-a.
Yun So-a.
It's all your fault.
Ini semua salahmu.
Do you know how I've lived?
Apa kau tahu
It's so unfair.
Sangat tidak adil.
Think carefully.
Pikirkan yang matang.
Does anyone hold a grudge against you?
Apa ada yang dendam kepadamu?
I think I should make a report.
Kurasa aku harus membuat laporan.
Someone was trying to kill you,
Ada yang mencoba membunuhmu,
and the king of the Land of Water saved you.
dan Dewa Negeri Air menyelamatkanmu.
You can't say that to anyone.
Jangan bilang-bilang.
He's right.
Dia benar.
But still...
Tapi tetap saja…
It's driving me crazy. What should I do?
Ini membuatku gila. Aku harus bagaimana?
Why do you come to work at different times every day?
Kenapa kau ke kantor di waktu berbeda setiap hari?
A patient had to go back. She seemed to suffer from paranoia and neurosis.
Pasien harus kembali. Sepertinya mengidap paranoia dan neurosis.
She would've stayed for at least two years.
Harusnya dia rawat inap dua tahun.
Hey,
Hei...
I almost died yesterday.
aku hampir mati kemarin.
-What? -I visited Yeom-mi.
- Apa? - Aku mengunjungi Yeom-mi.
A man dragged me to the rooftop and pushed me off.
Seorang pria menyeretku ke atap dan mendorongku.
As I was falling, I thought I'd die.
Saat aku jatuh, kukira aku akan mati.
Suddenly, the king of the Land of Water appeared and saved me.
Tiba-tiba, Raja Negeri Air muncul dan menyelamatkanku.
He wasn't handsome.
Dia tidak tampan.
What is with you these days? Do you want to become a different person?
Kau kenapa belakangan ini?
Among our patients,
Di antara pasien kita,
is there anyone who hates me?
apa ada yang membenciku?
There is. Mr. Ma Bong-yeol. You know that.
Ada, TN. Ma Bong-yeol. Kau tahu itu.
-Do you want me to read it out? -Hey.
- Mau kubacakan? - Hei.
Could anyone...
Apakah ada seseorang
Is there anyone who might want to kill me?
Apa ada yang ingin membunuhku?
There are many of those. Didn't you know that?
Ada banyak sekali. Kau tak tahu, ya?
What?
Apa?
Hyeong-sik, Min-cheol, Hye-jeong,
Hyeong-sik, Min-cheol, Hye-jeong,
Hyeon-a, Seo-won, Seong-bae, and some others.
Hyeon-a, Seo-won, Seong-bae, dan lainnya.
I can't even count them all on my fingers.
Jariku tidak muat menghitungnya.
Who are they?
Siapa mereka?
You don't know? My friends.
Kau tak tahu? Teman-temanku.
How would I know who your friends are?
Mana kutahu soal teman-temanmu?
Also, why would they hate me?
Kenapa mereka membenciku?
You don't remember?
Kau tak ingat?
Happy birthday to you
Selamat ulang tahun.
A beggar's birthday cake doesn't taste good.
Kue ulang tahun gelandangan rasanya tidak enak.
Take it off. It's my jacket.
Lepaskan. Itu jaketku.
Take it off.
Lepaskan.
Don't cry.
Jangan menangis.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Sang-yu, move.
Sang-yu, minggir.
Move.
Minggir.
You were very little, but you were so mean.
Kau dulu sangat kecil, tapi kau jahat sekali.
We used to say
Kami dulu suka berkata
we would kill you when we grew up.
kami akan membunuhmu saat dewasa nanti.
We were just kids then.
Namanya juga anak-anak.
We still talk about those days when we get together.
Kami masih membicarakan masa-masa kita bersama.
You're making me feel nostalgic.
Kau membuatku bernostalgia.
I had a birthday cake today instead of yesterday.
Aku punya kue ulang tahun hari ini, bukan kemarin.
Dad gave me the best part, the cherry and the chocolate.
Ayah memberiku bagian terenak, ceri dan cokelat.
MY BIRTHDAY
ULANG TAHUNKU
I can't believe you.
Aku tak percaya padamu.
Why did you take it away from me?
Kenapa kau mengambilnya dariku?
It's not too small for me.
Tidak terlalu kecil untukku.
Even if it becomes small for me or gets holes, it'll still be mine.
Walau itu mengecil atau berlubang, tetap jadi milikku.
I told him I wanted sausages so many times.
Aku bilang berkali-kali aku sangat ingin sosis.
And he gives me only kimchi.
Dan dia hanya memberiku kimchi.
I did nothing wrong.
Aku tak salah.
I'm the victim.
Aku korban.
She left keys for us.
Dia meninggalkan kunci untuk kita.
She said we could eat anything in the fridge.
Dia bilang kita bisa makan apa saja di kulkas.
This is something called a fridge.
Ini yang disebut kulkas.
I feel sorry for Ms. Descendant.
Aku kasihan pada Nn. Keturunan.
Are these clothes?
Apa ini pakaian?
That was all I could find in the recycling bin.
Hanya itu yang ada di tempat daur ulang.
I can't go like this.
Aku tak bisa keluar seperti ini.
Then let's go tomorrow. I have to work today too.
Baik, kita pergi besok. Hari ini aku kerja.
Call a taxi.
Panggil taksi.
You can eat alone. I'm fine.
Kau bisa makan sendiri. Aku tak apa.
It's important to have three meals a day. You don't know that?
Sangat penting untuk makan tiga kali sehari.
I don't want to go out today.
Aku tak mau keluar hari ini.
Why not?
Kenapa tidak?
Did you take private loans? Are your creditors here?
Kau ambil pinjaman?
-You've been acting strange. -That's not it.
- Kau bersikap aneh. - Bukan begitu.
You should never take private loans.
Jangan pernah mengambil pinjaman pribadi.
-How much did you borrow? -Fine, I'll go.
- Berapa banyak yang kau pinjam? - Baik, aku pergi.
I'll eat.
Aku akan makan.
You can't take private loans.
Kau jangan ambil pinjaman pribadi.
-I'll come after locking the door. -Okay.
- Aku kembali setelah mengunci pintu. - Baik.
Gosh.
Astaga.
I'd be much happier without him.
Aku akan lebih bahagia tanpanya.
Gosh!
Astaga!
What's wrong?
Ada apa?
Nothing. I'm sorry.
Tak ada. Maaf.
I was going to ask for directions, and you treat me like a pervert.
Aku ingin tanya arah dan kau perlakukanku seperti mesum.
What the hell?
Apa-apaan?
I'll probably die young.
Aku mungkin akan mati muda.
What's that?
Apa itu?
What is going on?
Ada apa ini?
Woman.
Wanita.
Servant!
Pelayan.
Hello.
Halo.
What is going on? How did you...
Ada apa? Bagaimana kau...
-You probably took a taxi. -I need clothes.
- Kau pasti naik taksi. - Aku butuh pakaian.
If I show up like this, Mura would feel humiliated.
Jika pakaianku begini, Mura akan merasa dipermalukan.
-Why are you asking me? -Who is that?
- Kenapa kau tanya aku? - Siapa itu?
Who...
Siapa...
Oh, you look familiar.
Kau tampak familier.
Hurry.
Cepat.
Wait.
Tunggu.
Take your hands off him.
Lepaskan tanganmu darinya.
Take your hands off. Who do you think you're stopping?
Lepas tanganmu. Kau pikir kau bicara dengan siapa?
-Take your hands off first. -I can't believe you.
- Lepaskan tanganmu darinya. - Aku tak percaya kau.
-Let go. -What?
- Lepaskan. - Apa?
-Stop it!
- Hentikan.
My gosh, you have a good eye.
Astaga, seleramu bagus.
You wouldn't expect it from suits hung here,
Kau takkan sangka ada setelan begini di sini,
Doesn't it look so sleek?
Terlihat rapi, 'kan?
How much is it?
Berapa harganya?
150,000 won.
150.000 won.
This would go for a million won at department stores.
Ini akan bernilai satu juta won di toserba.
It's just because this is a no-name shop. Isn't it extremely unfair?
Hanya karena ini toko tanpa nama. Kejam, ya?
-Can you give me a discount? -I'll give you 5,000 won off.
- Bisa beri aku diskon? - Kuberi diskon 5.000 won.
That's the fun part of shopping at markets, right?
Itu bagian asyik belanja di pasar, 'kan?
By the way, isn't this for him? Why is he standing over there?
Ini untuknya, 'kan? Kenapa dia berdiri di sana?
Shouldn't he try it on?
Bukankah dia harus coba?
He's mad as it's not a designer brand.
Dia marah, ini bukan merek desainer.
Goodness, who cares about brands?
Astaga, siapa yang peduli soal merek?
Don't you know that it's all about the person?
Yang penting si pemakai tahu?
You have such a nice body.
Badanmu bagus sekali.
You'll make any clothes look expensive.
Kau akan membuat pakaian tampak mahal.
Why would you want to waste money when you have such a perfect body?
Kenapa kau membuang-buang uang jika kau punya tubuh sempurna?
I can give you another 10,000 won off
Aku bisa memberimu 10.000 won
if you can take a photo of him in this suit.
jika kau memotretnya dengan jas ini.
I want to hang the photo here.
Kugantung fotonya di sini.
-Deal! -Deal.
- Setuju! - Setuju.
Why did you even take me to the department store?
Kenapa kau bahkan membawaku ke toserba?
That was my way of getting back at you.
Itu caraku membalasmu.
Having to eat pork belly must be tough when you're used to rib eye.
Pasti sulit makan perut babi jika terbiasa makan iga.
-What? -Aren't you hungry?
- Apa? - Kau tidak lapar?
We still have time until Namsuri gets back.
Masih ada waktu sampai Namsuri kembali.
I'm a god.
Aku dewa.
I don't feel lowly desires like hunger.
Aku tak punya nafsu rendahan seperti rasa lapar.
I heard the voracious deity kissed you.
Kudengar dewa rakus menciummu.
You should eat. I bet there's no cure to treat a god that faints.
Kau harus makan.
Cut it out.
Hentikan itu.
Goodness!
Astaga.
Seriously.
Yang benar saja.
Here, have this.
Ini, makanlah.
What do you think you're doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
I wouldn't be doing this if Namsuri hadn't asked me so earnestly.
Aku takkan begini jika Namsuri tidak memohon-mohon.
I'm sweating buckets in this heat to serve you well.
Aku berkeringat kepanasan begini untuk melayanimu.
Please try to be considerate of your servant here,
Tolong hargai pelayanmu ini
-although I don't understand this. -You're too chatty.
- meski aku tak mengerti ini. - Kau cerewet sekali.
About that goddess, Mura or whatever her name is,
Soal dewi itu, Mura atau siapa pun namanya...
do you think she'll help you this time?
Apa dia akan membantumu kali ini?
Yes.
Ya.
It seems like you have unconditional trust in her.
Sepertinya kau sangat percaya padanya.
Yes. With Mura, I do.
Ya, aku percaya pada Mura.
I guess it's possible
Kurasa mungkin bisa
to have unconditional trust in someone.
punya rasa percaya tanpa syarat pada seseorang.
Don't you think it's dumb, though?
Bukankah menurutmu itu bodoh?
Why don't you have someone like that?
Kenapa kau tak punya orang seperti itu?
-What do you mean? -Someone whom you can fully trust.
- Maksudnya? - Orang yang kau percaya sepenuhnya.
Someone who's always on your side, no matter what.
Yang selalu ada untukmu, apa pun yang terjadi.
You should have at least one person like that.
Setidaknya kau harus punya satu.
If the person whom you trust betrays you, you'll come to understand
Jika yang kau percaya berkhianat, kau akan mengerti
how futile that belief is.
bahwa keyakinan itu sia-sia.
Excuse me, could we have some warm water here?
Permisi, bisa minta air hangat?
Sure
Tentu.
Why do you want to drink warm water in this heat?
Kenapa kau mau minum air hangat saat cuaca panas begini?
-Is your stomach upset? -Yes.
- Apa perutmu sakit? - Ya.
-You don't like cold water? -No.
- Kau tak suka air dingin? - Tidak.
-Why? -Because it's cold.
- Kenapa? - Karena dingin.
Did you jump in the water in the middle of winter?
Kau melompat ke air di tengah musim dingin?
Why did you want to die?
Kenapa kau ingin mati?
What...
Apa...
What are you talking about? Goodness!
Apa maksudmu? Astaga.
Why would I want to die?
Buat apa aku mau mati?
Was it because of the person who betrayed you?
Apa karena orang yang mengkhianatimu?
-How foolish. -Look--
- Konyol sekali. - Lihat.
-Hello? -I'm here.
- Halo? - Aku di sini.
-Where should I go? -We'll come to you. Okay.
- Aku harus ke mana? - Kami akan menghampirimu.
Let's go if you're not going to eat.
Ayo pergi jika kau tak makan.
Yes, where are you now?
Ya, kau di mana sekarang?
A servant of the God of Water can't be afraid of water.
Pelayan Dewa Air tak boleh takut air.
It just doesn't make sense.
Itu tak masuk akal.
What doesn't make sense is your...
Yang tak masuk akal adalah...
How about we do a little deal?
Bagaimana kalau kita buat kesepakatan?
If you do me a favor, I'll do the same for you.
Jika kau membantuku, aku juga membanumu.
I have no favor to ask you.
Aku mau minta bantuan.
Please don't call me your servant.
Kumohon jangan panggil aku pelayanmu.
Your turn. Anything but buying you a designer suit.
Giliranmu. Apa pun selain setelan desainer.
I'll count down from five. You'll lose your chance after that.
Kuhitung dari lima. Setelah itu tidak bisa.
-Five, four, three, two, one. -I have no favor to ask you,
Aku tak minta apa-apa,
but I do want to warn you of something. I'll give you a warning instead.
hanya memperingatkan.
-"A warning"? -That's right.
- "Peringatan"? - Benar.
Don't fall for me.
Jangan jatuh cinta padaku.
There's no way out
Tak ada jalan keluar jika kau jatuh cinta padaku.
You're seriously something.
Kau ini memang aneh.
I've warned you.
Aku memperingatkanmu.
Deal.
Setuju.
"There's no way out"?
Tak ada jalan keluar?
Was that supposed to be a joke?
Apa itu lelucon?
Was it a parody or satire?
Apakah itu parodi atau sindiran?
Was he actually being serious?
Apa dia serius?
Unbelievable.
Tak bisa dipercaya.
I'll hit the jackpot if I open a clinic in the divine world.
Aku akan untung besar jika buka klinik di alam surgawi.
Shall I emigrate there?
Apa aku pindah saja?
-Hey, what's up? -Where are you?
- Hei, apa kabar? - Kau di mana?
I'm in front of the clinic.
Aku di depan klinik.
I told you not to worry about them.
Sudah kubilang jangan cemaskan mereka.
They're just neighbors.
Mereka hanya tetangga.
-If you keep nagging like this-- -The land might get sold.
- Jika kau merengek terus... - Tanahnya mungkin sudah terjual.
What?
Apa?
-Beriwon Resort? -That windshield guy's company.
- Resor Beriwon? - Perusahaan kaca mobil itu.
I heard that company will build a resort there.
Kudengar perusahaan itu akan membangun resor di sana.
Do you want to know what's crazy? A road will be built there too.
Kau mau tahu hal gila? Di sana akan dibangun jalan juga.
It means that they need your land in order to build their resort.
Artinya mereka butuh tanahmu untuk membangun resor.
Then shall I ask them for more money?
Kalau begitu, aku bisa minta uang pada mereka?
No, wait. How about I ask for five times the market price?
Tidak, tunggu. Bagaimana kalau aku minta lima kali lipat harga pasar?
-What is it? -Hello?
- Ada apa? - Halo?
Who is it?
Siapa itu?
Yes, she's back.
Ya, dia kembali.
It's the resort.
Ini soal resor.
Hello? Yes, I'm the landowner.
Halo? Ya, aku pemilik tanah.
Yes, of course. I'm interested in selling it.
Ya, tentu saja. Aku tertarik menjualnya.
-Then can we meet with you today? -Yes, of course.
- Bisa bertemu denganmu hari ini? - Ya, tentu.
Hello?
Halo?
I can make some time to meet with you today, but...
Aku bisa menemuimu hari ini, tapi…
Great. Shall we meet you at your clinic?
Bagus. Bisa kita bertemu di klinikmu?
No.
Tidak.
Please have your CEO call me.
Minta CEO-mu untuk meneleponku.
I have about five minutes until my next patient arrives.
Aku punya waktu sekitar lima menit sampai pasien berikutnya tiba.
Well, then. I'll be waiting.
Kalau begitu, kutunggu, ya.
What was that about?
Apa maksudmu tadi?
I should enjoy having the upper hand.
Aku senang berada di atas angin.
That jerk has been mocking me like there's no tomorrow.
Bajingan itu mengejekku habis-habisan.
You should work harder to earn money.
Kau harus bekerja lebih keras untuk mencari uang.
Then I'd like you to pay the price.
Maka aku ingin kau membayarnya.
Wait, that's not what I meant...
Tunggu, bukan itu yang kumaksud…
That nasty temper of yours is coming out again.
Temperamen menjijikkanmu itu keluar lagi.
What do if playing hard to get makes them give up?
Lalu jika mereka mundur karena kau jual mahal?
Let's just wait.
Tunggu saja.
Thank you for calling Blessed Mental Health.
Terima kasih sudah menghubungi Klinik Jiwa Blessed.
This is Director Yun So-a.
Ini Direktur Yun So-a.
This is Shin Hu-ye.
Ini Shin Hu-ye.
Lady Mura is truly impressive.
Nyonya Mura sangat mengesankan.
She's found a way to live as a goddess even in the human realm.
Dia menemukan cara hidup sebagai dewi bahkan di alam manusia.
I just wish her personality was more graceful.
Andai saja kepribadiannya lebih anggun.
Thank goodness she can't use her power on humans.
Syukurlah dia tak bisa memakai kekuatannya untuk manusia.
-This is crazy. -Many could've been harmed.
- Ini gila. - Bisa banyak korban.
She doesn't throw fits for no reason.
Dia tak berulah tanpa alasan.
You had to go through that because you always coddle her like that.
Kau harus melalui itu karena kau selalu memanjakannya.
If she finds out about you losing your power,
Jika dia tahu kau keliangan kekuatanmu,
she'll look down on you.
dia akan pikir dia menguasaimu.
That's why you can't tell her.
Itu sebabnya jangan memberitahunya.
Make sure you watch your mouth.
Pastikan kau jaga mulutmu.
What does that mean?
Apa maksudnya?
Lady Mura.
Nyonya Mura.
You lost what?
Kau kehilangan apa?
You've lost... your power?
Kau kehilangan...
Can you recognize me now?
Kau bisa mengenaliku?
What ticked you off?
Apa yang memancingmu?
What do you mean you lost your power?
Apa maksudnya kekuatanmu hilang?
Don't worry. It's just temporary.
Jangan khawatir. Ini hanya sementara.
It'll come back soon.
Nanti segera kembali.
It was so hard.
Sulit sekali.
We had no way of finding you and had nowhere to go.
Kami tak bisa menemukanmu dan tak punya tujuan.
He knew nothing about this world.
Dia tak tahu soal dunia ini.
He had no power, so he lost to the voracious deity.
Dia tak punya kekuatan, jadi dia kalah pada dewa yang rakus.
-Voracious deity? -You know Jugeollin, right?
- Dewa yang rakus? - Kau tahu Jugeollin, 'kan?
He challenged Lord Habaek out of the blue.
Dia tiba-tiba menantang Tuan Habaek.
He fled our land, and it turned out he was here.
Dia kabur, ternyata dia di sini.
We found the divine servant, so we asked for help,
Kami menemukan abdi surgawi, jadi kami meminta bantuan,
-but it doesn't look good. -A divine servant?
- tapi hasilnya tidak bagus. - Abdi surgawi?
Then that woman was...
Lantas wanita itu…
She's shockingly stupid. I need to move into your place.
Ternyata dia sangat bodoh.
Where are Biryeom and Judong?
Di mana Biryeom dan Judong?
I'll take your sacred stone first, so get it ready for me.
Aku akan ambil batu keramatmu dulu, jadi siapkan untukku.
Hello, Ms. Yun.
Halo, Nn. Yun.
Isn't this place a bit secluded to talk business?
Bukankah tempat ini agak terpencil untuk membicarakan bisnis?
I had a feeling you didn't want to discuss business.
Aku merasa kau tak mau membahas bisnis.
Why else would I want to see you?
Untuk apa lagi aku ingin menemuimu?
To discuss the windshield wipers?
Untuk membahas penyeka kaca mobil?
To discuss bank loans?
Untuk membahas pinjaman bank?
Have a seat.
Silakan duduk.
About my land that you're interested in...
Tentang tanahku yang kau minati…
Someone else at my company is handling that. Why--
Orang lain di perusahaanku sedang menanganinya. Kenapa...
Negotiate?
Tawar-menawar?
I heard you needed my land.
Kudengar kau butuh tanahku.
-That's correct. -I want five times its value.
- Benar. - Aku ingin harganya lima kali lipat.
No negotiations.
Tidak bisa ditawar.
No.
Tidak.
-What? -I can't give you the sacred stone.
- Apa? - Aku tak bisa memberimu batu keramat.
And I don't know where Biryeom and Judong are.
Biryeom dan Judong entah di mana.
-You can't move in either. -What?
- Kau tak bisa pindah ke sini. - Apa?
Did you forget? The guardians of the sacred stones
Apa kau lupa? Para penjaga batu keramat
decide whether or not to give away the sacred stones.
memutuskan apakah akan memberi batu keramat atau tidak.
Lady Mura. Please calm yourself down.
Nyonya Mura, tenangkan dirimu.
That goes against the rules.
Itu melanggar peraturan.
All the guardians of the sacred stones
Semua penjaga batu keramat
had protected them
telah melindungi batu-batu itu
and gave them to the succeeding king--
dan memberikannya pada raja berikutnya...
How dare you get involved?
Beraninya kau ikut campur?
How can we have a powerless god as our king?
Bagaimana bisa dewa tanpa kekuatan menjadi raja kita?
Look at you.
Lihat dirimu.
If you are qualified to be king,
Jika kau layak menjadi raja,
Biryeom and Judong should be standing before you.
Biryeom dan Judong harusnya menghadapmu.
However, you don't even know where they are.
Tapi kau tak tahu di mana mereka.
No?
Tidak?
Okay, then I won't sell.
Baik, takkan kujual.
Your land is the most critical, so we had decided
Tanahmu itu yang paling penting, jadi kami memutuskan
to offer you seven times the value, unlike the others.
menawarkan tujuh kali lipat dari yang lain.
If you'd be upset at being treated differently,
Jika kau marah karena diperlakukan berbeda,
we will pay five times the value just like everyone else.
kami akan bayar lima kali lipat seperti yang lain.
You say you won't negotiate, so we have no choice.
Kau bilang tak membuka tawaran, jadi kami tak punya pilihan.
I'll have him bring the contract, so you can look it over.
Akan kuminta dia membawa kontraknya, agar kau bisa lihat.
I won't sell.
Aku takkan menjualnya.
Goodness, it was supposed to be a joke.
Astaga, ini seharusnya hanya lelucon.
In other words, you aren't qualified to become the king.
Dengan kata lain, kau tak layak menjadi raja.
-I'm not qualified? -That's right.
- Aku tak layak? - Benar.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
What must I do for you to give it to me?
Aku harus apa agar kau memberikannya padaku?
-What? -What must I do for you
- Apa? - Apa yang harus kulakukan untukmu
to acknowledge I'm qualified?
agar diakui bahwa aku memenuhi syarat?
-For me? -That's right!
- Untukku? - Benar!
-Don't come any closer. -Tell me!
- Jangan mendekat. - Katakan!
Report everyone who posted negative comments about me online.
Laporkan semua komentar buruk terhadapku di daring.
Shoot! Seven times.
Sial. Tujuh kali liipat.
Seven times.
Tujuh kali lipat.
-What have I done? -Isn't she the woman that we know?
- Apa yang kulakukan? - Bukankah kita mengenalnya?
Ms. Descendant!
Nona Keturunan!
That's right. He said he was coming here.
Benar.
-What are you doing here? -Well...
- Sedang apa kau di sini? - Aku...
I came to see a friend.
aku datang untuk menemui teman.
A friend? That strange woman from last time?
Teman? Wanita aneh itu?
Did everything go well? Are you moving into Hye-ra's place now?
Apa urusanmu lancar? Apa kau pindah ke rumah Hye-ra sekarang?
-What are negative comments? -What?
- Apa itu komentar negatif? - Apa?
What you blurted out was to report people posting negative comments?
Kau memintanya melaporkan orang yang berkomentar negatif?
I was caught off guard.
Aku panik seketika.
I didn't expect that reaction.
Aku tak bermaksud bereaksi begitu.
You lost it when he asked what he could do for you.
Kau hilang akal saat dia tanya dia bisa apa untukmu.
-That's not it. The sacred stones-- -What else did you ask for?
- Bukan begitu. Batu keramat itu... - Kau minta apa lagi?
She wants you to be her bodyguard at her signing event?
Dia minta kau mengawal di acara penandatanganannya?
That's right.
Benar.
What's a bodyguard?
Apa itu pengawal?
Is she really a goddess?
Apa dia benar-benar dewi?
She acts like a bitter teenage girl.
Sikapnya seperti remaja perempuan yang getir.
Ms. Yun.
Nn. Yun.
I see you have company.
Sedang bersama teman, ya.
Please let me clear up the misunderstanding
Tolong izinkan aku meluruskan kesalahpahaman
and give me a second chance to negotiate with you.
dan beri kesempatan kedua untuk bernegosiasi.
If you don't want to, maybe we can set a time tomorrow--
Jika kau tak mau, mungkin kita bisa mengatur waktu besok.
No.
Tidak, tidak.
Bye.
Sampai jumpa.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
Her friend looks like he has a lot of gold.
Temannya itu terlihat seperti punya banyak uang.
A joke?
Lelucon?
I don't think we're close enough to make jokes.
Kurasa kita tak cukup dekat untuk bercanda.
I want to get along with everyone, regardless of the relationship.
Aku ingin akur dengan semua orang, dalam hubungan apa pun.
Why?
Kenapa?
-What do you mean? -You can't get along with everyone.
- Apa maksudmu? - Kau tak bisa akur dengan semua orang.
Why not?
Kenapa tidak?
If you want to be nice to everyone,
Jika ingin baik kepada semua orang, kau harus selalu menahan emosimu.
Then you will likely find a poor victim
Lalu kau akan menemukan korban yang malang
onto whom you will release those repressed emotions.
yang akan jadi korban luapan emosi terpendammu.
In extreme cases, murderers--
Dalam kasus ekstrem, pembunuh…
I got carried away.
Aku terbawa suasana.
It's fine. It's your job.
Tak apa-apa. Itu pekerjaanmu.
I want to be a good person.
Aku ingin jadi orang baik.
I want to help those in need and give to society.
Aku ingin menolong orang yang membutuhkan dan menyumbang ke masyarakat.
I want to be someone who is useful to this world.
Aku ingin menjadi seseorang yang berguna bagi dunia ini.
Here's another teenager.
Lagi-lagi ada anak remaja.
-Can I not? -Not necessarily.
- Bisakah aku? - Belum tentu.
I knew someone like that,
Aku kenal orang seperti itu,
but the ending wasn't that great.
tapi akhirnya tidak sehebat itu.
Hello?
Halo?
You may go see Chairman Shin now.
Kau bisa menemui Direktur Shin sekarang.
Okay.
Baik.
Look over the contract. It's for seven times the value.
Bacalah kontraknya. Harganya jadi tujuh kali lipat.
Give me a call once you have.
Hubungi aku jika sudah.
Grandpa!
Kakek.
I want a talent agency!
- Aku ingin punya agensi bakat! - Diam!
I'm planning to add a mall in Block World,
Aku berencana menambah mal di Block World,
so you run that.
kau yang menjalankan.
You'll make much more than working as an entertainer.
Penghasilanmu akan lebih banyak daripada bekerja di dunia hiburan.
Darn it.
Sial.
I lost two buildings trying to make you a doctor.
Aku kehilangan dua gedung, demi menjadikanmu seorang dokter.
Why are you wasting your time after graduating from med school?
Kenapa membuang waktumu setelah lulus sekolah kedokteran?
What are you wearing?
Apa itu yang kau pakai?
He put me on a roller coaster and fed me jajangmyeon.
Aku naik kereta luncur sambil makan jajangmyeon.
My stupid agency didn't even give me a heads-up.
Agensi bodohku itu bahkan tak memberikan kabar dulu.
But I smiled and did it.
Tapi aku tetap melakukannya. Kenapa? Karena aku profesional.
That's why I'm asking you for a talent agency,
Itu sebabnya aku meminta agensi bakat,
so I don't have to put up with things like this.
jadi aku tak perlu menghadapi hal seperti ini.
Why, that...
Kenapa itu...
Go wash this.
Cuci ini.
Soak it in water.
Rendam di air.
Like a wet towel, as it's supposed to be.
Seperti selayaknya handuk basah.
No!
Tidak!
Why, that...
Kenapa itu...
Get back here!
Kembali!
Move!
Minggir!
Yes. I know it would be good for me to become a doctor.
Ya. Aku tahu akan baik untukku andai kujadi dokter.
But what can I do? I can't.
Tapi aku bisa apa? Tak ada.
What can I do? I'm stupid.
Aku bisa apa? Aku bodoh.
I know I'll make no money being a minor celebrity.
Aku tahu aku takkan bisa menghasilkan uang
But that's what I like.
Tapi itu yang kusuka.
Darn it.
Sial.
You make me sick.
Kau membuatku jijik.
-What? -Wipe your face.
- Apa? - Bersihkan wajahmu.
You're a star.
Kau seorang bintang.
Why do you care?
Kenapa kau peduli?
Hey. I don't need it. Take it back.
Hei. Aku tak membutuhkannya. Ambillah.
That jerk.
Dasar berengsek.
REAL ESTATE PURCHASE AGREEMENT
PERJANJIAN PEMBELIAN PERUMAHAN
Seven times. I can't believe it.
Tujuh kali lipat. Sulit dipercaya.
Oh, my gosh.
Astaga.
I can pinch harder for you.
Aku bisa mencubitmu lebih keras.
I'm going to be busy for a while.
Aku akan sibuk untuk sementara.
Finally.
Akhirnya.
An international driver's license.
SIM internasional.
An immunization report in English, proof of no criminal record, and what else?
Laporan imunisasi dalam bahasa Inggris, SKCK, lalu apa lagi?
The balance has been taken care of.
Masalahnya sudah diurus.
It'll cost millions in moving fees alone.
Perlu biaya jutaan untuk pindah saja.
Hey. I'll find you a job with a great clinic, so don't worry.
Akan kucarikan kau kerja di klinik yang bagus. Jangan khawatir.
I have plenty of offers.
Aku dapat banyak tawaran.
Let's have a drink to celebrate.
Ayo minum untuk merayakannya.
I have my side job.
Aku ada kerja sampingan.
Hey. Skip it.
Hei, bolos saja.
You drink a lukewarm, non-alcoholic drink like it's alcohol.
Kau minum minuman hangat tak beralkohol seperti alkohol.
I can't risk having any more bad luck.
Aku tak mau ambil risiko lagi.
Then why did we come to a bar?
Lalu kenapa kita ke bar?
Why do you hate Korea so much?
Kenapa kau benci sekali dengan Korea?
You're the weird one.
Kau yang aneh.
Haven't you heard "Korea is Hell on Earth"?
Kau tahu "Korea adalah Neraka Dunia"?
People in their twenties like you came up with that phrase.
Orang berusia 20-an sepertimu mencetuskan kalimat itu.
Everyone wants out.
Semuanya ingin pergi.
Still, I like Korea.
Tetap saja, aku suka Korea.
-What's the use? Korea hates you. -What?
Apa gunanya? Korea membencimu.
-Korea likes other people. -Who?
- Korea menyukai orang lain. - Siapa?
I met two people today who know nothing about how the world works.
Aku bertemu dua orang yang tak tahu cara kerja dunia.
No. One isn't a person. Anyway, do you know what they have in common?
Tidak, yang pertama itu bukan manusia. Omong-omong,
They were born with a silver spoon in their mouths.
Mereka terlahir sebagai orang yang kaya raya.
Life is a hobby for them.
Hidup adalah hobi bagi mereka.
That's why they could spout on
Itu sebabnya mereka bisa bicara tentang
about giving to society and helping others.
memberi kepada masyarakat dan membantu sesama.
Doctor.
Dokter.
But you know Korea loves people like them.
Tapi kau tahu, Korea menyukai orang seperti mereka.
Outwardly, they curse them, but they like them on the inside.
Di luar, mereka mengutuk. Di dalam, mereka suka.
And people like you are the opposite.
Orang sepertimu adalah kebalikannya.
Outwardly, they applaud you, but they hate you on the inside.
Di luar, mereka memujimu. Di dalam, mereka membencimu.
There's a reason no one comes to our clinic.
Ada alasan tak ada yang datang ke klinik kita.
He told me I had to take good care of you, but look at your mental state.
Dia bilang aku harus menjagamu dengan baik,
You're killing my buzz.
Kau membuatku tertekan.
Hey. Let's go singing.
Hei. Ayo kita bernyanyi.
"I hear Hye-ra is dating six guys at once.
"Katanya Hye-ra memacari enam pria sekaligus.
One per day of the week."
Satu sehari dalam sepekan."
"Silicon queen.
"Ratu silikon.
These things are negative comments.
Ini komentar-komentar negatif.
Poor Mura.
Mura yang malang.
She's having a rough time here too.
Dia juga mengalami masa sulit di sini.
If we click on this, you can report them.
Jika kita klik ini, kau bisa melaporkannya.
But you can't read Korean.
Tapi kau tak bisa baca bahasa Korea.
So you should study hangul first.
Jadi, kau harus belajar hangul dahulu.
This is G. This is N.
Ini G. Ini N.
R, ROUND M, MONEY
B, BUNDAR U, UANG
-Why isn't she home yet? -I'm sure she'll be back.
Kenapa dia belum pulang?
"The old witch tries to act cute."
"Nenek lampir berlagak sok manis."
Report.
Laporkan.
-What? -Keep it down.
- Apa? - Pelankan suaramu.
-What is that sound? -This isn't your home.
- Suara apa itu? - Ini bukan rumahmu.
Human men are drunk and fighting.
Manusia pria mabuk dan berkelahi.
All sorts of inexplicable things happen at night in the human world.
Hal-hal tak mampu dijelaskan terjadi di malam hari di dunia manusia.
That's nothing.
Itu bukan apa-apa.
-Why, you little... -Go ahead, hit me!
- Kenapa kau... - Ayo, pukul aku!
"When I watch her terrible acting, I...
"Saat kulihat aktingnya yang buruk,
I want to tear off her face."
ingin kurobek wajahnya."
"Tear off her face."
"Merobek wajahnya."
Report.
Lapor.
"I hope that I run into you...
"Kuharap aku berpapasan denganmu
on the street at night someday."
di jalan suatu malam."
Okay. Report.
Baiklah. Lapor.
"Last time..."
"Terakhir kali..."
He's really getting to me.
Dia makin membuatku kesal.
If you keep this up, I'll just sing a cappella.
Jika terus begini, aku akan bernyanyi akapela saja.
Hey.
Hei.
What are you doing here?
Kau sedang apa di sini?
I was thinking of ways to get my power back.
Aku memikirkan cara untuk mendapatkan kekuatanku kembali.
Why are you doing that here?
Kenapa melakukannya di sini?
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
Next time, think up there, where the alley meets the main road.
Lain kali, pikirkan saja di sana, di gang dekat jalan besar.
What is that smell?
Bau apa itu?
I brought some spicy chicken.
Aku membawa ayam pedas.
Something really good happened to me today,
Aku mengalami sesuatu yang sangat baik hari ini,
so it's my treat.
ini traktiran dariku.
I don't want it.
Aku tak mau.
Did you eat?
Kau sudah makan?
I told you. I don't need things like that.
Sudah kubilang. Aku tak butuh hal seperti itu.
Food.
Makanan.
-Stop it. -Okay.
- Hentikan. - Baiklah.
I get it now.
Aku mengerti sekarang.
You get hungry whenever I mention food.
Kau lapar setiap kali aku menyebut makanan.
I do not.
Tidak.
That's what you call "a response."
Itu yang kau sebut "respons".
Admit you've become a god that can now feel hungry.
Akuila,h kau sudah jadi dewa yang kini bisa merasa lapar.
It's a huge realization.
Itu kesadaran besar.
Why, that woman...
Kenapa wanita itu...
Food!
Makanan!
This is so funny.
Ini lucu sekali.
Why are you in such a good mood?
Kenapa suasana hatimu baik sekali?
I met...
Aku bertemu...
a real god today.
dewa sejati hari ini.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
Who's deceiving you this time?
Siapa yang menipumu kali ini?
Not everyone who's handsome is a god.
Tidak semua yang tampan adalah dewa.
What is a god?
Apa itu dewa?
What?
Apa?
A superior being that grants humans their most desperate wishes.
Makhluk agung yang memberi harapan terbesar kepada manusia.
That is a true god.
Itu dewa sejati.
I...
Aku...
I am a real god.
Aku dewa sejati.
Sure.
Tentu.
Did you finish reporting the negative... That's right.
Apa kau sudah selesai melaporkan... Oh, iya.
You can't read Korean.
Kau tak bisa baca bahasa Korea.
YUN SO-A
YUN SO-A
-You can write? -You should be honored.
- Kau bisa menulis? - Seharusnya kau tersanjung.
That's the first thing I've ever written.
Itu hal pertama yang kutulis.
This is how to write my name.
Ini cara menulis namaku.
HABAK
HABAK.
Goodness.
Astaga.
HABAEK
HABAEK
YUN SO-A
HABAEK, YUN SO-A
What is this?
Apa ini?
-Please eat. -Forget it.
- Makanlah. - Lupakan.
-I've seen you. -What?
- Aku pernah melihatmu. - Apa?
That day, by the Han River. After I left, you picked up--
Tempo hari, di tepi Sungai Han. Setelah aku pergi, kau mengambil…
That's what you get for talking about "your side" and "my side".
Itu akibatnya dari membicarakan "sisimu" dan "sisiku".
You've experienced the pain of betrayal
Kau merasakan rasa dikhianati dan juga lapar.
You should've become a better king yesterday
Kau seharusnya jadi raja yang lebih baik
than the day before, and today than yesterday.
daripada kemarin dan daripada kemarin lusa.
What was that?
Apa itu?
I'm saying you're learning how to be a king properly.
Aku bilang kau belajar menjadi raja dengan baik.
So? Did you figure out what a bodyguard is?
Jadi, apa kau sudah tahu apa itu pengawal?
Yes. Since I learned how to read...
Ya. Sejak aku belajar membaca...
There's a movie called The Bodyguard.
Ada film berjudul Bodyguard.
-He watched it. -It's pretty cool.
- Dia menontonnya. - Filmnya keren.
It's worth experiencing at least once.
Layak dialami setidaknya sekali.
He underestimates humans.
Dia meremehkan manusia.
She's here.
Dia di sini.
Please clear a path.
Tolong kosongkan jalan.
-Lord Habaek! -Let go.
- Tuan Habaek! - Lepaskan.
Let go!
Lepaskan!
-Stop pushing! -Stop it!
- Jangan dorong! - Hentikan!
Don't come any closer!
Jangan datang! Tidak!
Stop it!
Hentikan!
No. You can't get hurt.
Tidak. Kau tak boleh terluka.
No.
Tidak.
What's wrong with you people?
Kalian inikenapa?
Why are they like that?
Kenapa mereka seperti itu?
Why?
Kenapa?
You think I'm a failure, don't you?
Kau pikir aku orang gagal, 'kan?
You just touched your nose.
Kau baru saja menyentuh hidungmu.
They say when you lie, your hormones make your nose itch.
Mereka bilang saat kau berbohong, hormonmu membuat hidungmu gatal.
That's why you touch it without realizing it.
Jadi kau menyentuhnya tanpa sadar.
No, I scratched my nose because it itched.
Tidak, aku menggaruk hidungku karena gatal.
You yawned last week and the week before for the same reason.
Kau menguap minggu lalu dan minggu sebelumnya
It's been two hours already, So-min.
Sudah dua jam, So-min.
You've been nitpicking everything I do.
Kau mencereweti semua yang kulakukan.
-That makes your treatment-- -Forget it.
- Itu membuat pengobatanmu... - Lupakan.
I'm suddenly in a bad mood!
Suasana hatiku jadi jelek!
YUN SO-A
YUN SO-A
Hold it in. You can do it.
Tahan. Kau bisa melakukannya.
Hold it in.
Tahan.
-Are you going to keep doing this? -Sorry.
- Kau akan terus melakukan ini? - Maaf.
I just can't.
Aku tak bisa.
I can't trust an heir to the throne who doesn't have his power.
Aku tak bisa memercayai pewaris takhta yang tak punya kekuatan.
Lady Mura...
Nyonya Mura.
Darn it.
Sial.
I'm losing my mind here.
Aku jadi gila.
-Hello? -I can't do it anymore.
- Halo? - Aku tak sanggup lagi.
You do it.
Kau saja.
You want my what?
Kau mau apa dariku?
I'm stressed out, so I need to go for a drive.
Aku stres, jadi aku harus pergi berkendara.
Give me your car keys.
Jadi, berikan kunci mobilmu.
Go home.
Pulanglah.
I'll pick the lock if you refuse.
Akan kubobol kuncinya jika kau menolak.
What was that?
Apa tadi?
I'll look online.
Akan kucari daring.
I've memorized the workings of a car already, anyway.
Aku sudah hafal cara kerja mobil.
I said I want to drive.
Kubilang aku ingin menyetir.
I want to kill him.
Aku ingin membunuhnya.
Isn't there anything online
Bukankah di daring ada kiat-kiat untuk membunuh dewa?
Hey. That's blasphemy.
Hei. Itu hujatan.
Fine, let's do this.
Baiklah, mari kita lakukan.
I'm stressed out today too, so let's go.
Aku stres hari ini. Jadi, ayo pergi.
-I will drive. -Buckle up.
- Aku yang mengemudi. - Pakai sabuk pengaman.
You can reimburse me for gas.
Gantikan uang bensinku.
You're cutting off my neck.
Kau memotong leherku.
It's fine as long as I'm in it.
Bagus asal aku kelihatan.
Come here.
Kemarilah.
I guess my car wasn't enough.
Kurasa mobilku tak cukup.
Your car's engine sounds strange.
Mesin mobilmu terdengar aneh.
The exhaust is loud too.
Knalpotnya juga berisik.
There's a squeaking sound coming from under the hood.
Terdengar suara berdecit dari balik kap mesin.
You just need to tighten the wheel bearing.
Cukup kencangkan saja pelek bannya.
When did you last have it inspected?
Kapan terakhir diperiksa?
I'm speechless.
Aku kehabisan kata-kata.
Can you really learn anything and do anything
Apa benar kau bisa belajar dan melakukan apa pun
after seeing it or reading it once?
setelah melihatnya atau membacanya sekali?
Even without your power?
Bahkan tanpa kekuatanmu?
It has nothing to do with my power. That's what makes me a god.
Tak ada hubungannya dengan kekuatanku.
Mr. Nature, I have a question.
Tn. Alam, aku punya pertanyaan.
Who's Lady Yuhwa's mom?
Siapa ibu Nyonya Yuhwa?
I can't find it anywhere.
Aku tak bisa menemukannya.
-Who's Lady Yuhwa? -Your daughter.
- Siapa Nyonya Yuhwa? - Putrimu.
Jumong's mom. King Yuri's maternal grandmother.
Ibunya Jumong. Nenek dari pihak ibu Raja Yuri.
You're King Yuri's maternal grandfather.
Kau kakek dari garis ibu Raja Yuri.
So who's your wife?
Jadi, siapa istrimu?
I've never been married.
Aku belum menikah.
There's no use pretending to be single.
Tak ada gunanya pura-pura lajang.
I had...
Aku mengalami
a really tough day today.
hari yang berat tadi.
It would've been nice...
Pasti lebih baik
if you had your power.
andai kekuatanmu ada.
If you had your power,
Jika kau punya kekuatan,
would you be able to create an ocean full of reefs for me?
apa kau bisa menciptakan samudra penuh karang untukku?
Of course.
Tentu saja.
A white sand beach...
Pantai berpasir putih
filled with sunshine too?
disirami sinar matahari juga?
I want to go into the ocean.
Aku ingin menyelami samudra.
I can see...
Aku bisa
the ocean.
melihat samudra.
I want to swim.
Aku mau berenang.
The water doesn't scare me.
Air tak membuatku takut.
I'm alone, but I'm not lonely.
Aku sendirian, tapi aku tidak kesepian.
-What are you doing? -You can't be alone.
- Apa yang kau lakukan? - Kau tak bisa sendirian.
I need to be there for me to use my power.
Aku harus ada untuk menggunakan kekuatanku.
Darn it.
Sial.
I want to be alone.
Aku ingin sendiri.
What is this now?
Apa lagi sekarang?
You can't swim.
Kau tak bisa berenang.
I'm swimming now.
Aku sedang berenang sekarang.
Really? I'll let go then.
Sungguh? Kalau begitu, aku melepasmu.
No, hold on.
Tidak, tunggu.
Darn. I'm sure I was able to swim earlier.
Sial. Aku yakin dulu aku bisa berenang.
Why do I suddenly feel like I won't be able to?
Kenapa tiba-tiba aku merasa tak bisa?
Leave it to me.
Serahkan kepadaku.
I'll keep you safe, at least when you're in the water.
Aku akan menjagamu tetap aman saat berada di air.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
For what?
Untuk apa?
Did you try to kill me on purpose?
Apa kau sengaja mencoba membunuhku?
When you start something, you need to finish it.
Saat kau memulai, kau harus menyelesaikannya.
How can a god be so selfish?
Kenapa dewa seegois itu?
You won't be able to live the way you want.
Kau takkan bisa hidup sesuai keinginanmu.
-A divine servant? -Who cares about that?
- Abdi surgawi? - Siapa peduli?
No, I can't.
Tidak, aku tak bisa.
I'm getting excited. It's been a while since we worked together to get Habaek.
Aku bersemangat.
You guys, how can you be this irresponsible?
Bagaimana kau bisa tak bertanggung jawab begini?
Don't tell me you're doing this because of her.
Jangan bilang kau melakukan ini karena dia.
Thank you for saving my life.
Terima kasih sudah menyelamatkanku.
I promise you that I'll protect you.
Aku janji.